在上一节中，我们假设我们
in the last section we assume that we
总是以相同的格式获取 post 参数
always get post parameters in the same format
但情况并非总是如此
but that's not always the case
让我们看看这个帖子请求
let's have a look at this post request
再次
again
在上一节中，我们暗示了这种内容类型
in the last section we hinted that this content type
有点重要
was kind of important
当内容类型设置为此值时
when the content type is set to this value
这意味着正文是一个查询字符串
it means that the body is a query string
以这个名字编码
encoded in this name
我们在这里看到的值对格式
value pair format that we see down here
所以内容类型有效地告诉我们如何解析
so the content type effectively tells us how to parse
请求正文
the request body
现在您还可以发布不同编码的数据
now you can also post data encoded differently
所以检查内容类型很重要
so it's important to check the content type
确定如何解析body
to determine how to parse the body
为此，我们需要解析所有这些标头
to do that we need to parse all of these headers
和我们
and we
现在已经将它们作为字符串列表
already have them right now as a list of strings
所以我们添加了一些日志记录以便我们可以看到
so we've added a bit of logging so that we can see that
所以这是我们的标题作为字符串列表
so here is our headers as a list of strings
但是将其转换为具有键值对的映射
but transforming this into a map with key value pairs
那会更有用
well that would be so much more useful
所以要在我们的合作和 v 中进行设置
so to set this up over in our co and v struck
类似于我们如何将 para 作为一个字段
similar to how we have para as a field
它有一个空地图的默认值
and it has a default value of empty map
我们想对标题做同样的事情
what we want to do the same thing with headers
所以我们会有一个 headers 字段
so we'll have a headers field
它也将默认为空地图
and it'll also default to an empty map
然后在类似于 prams 的 parse 函数中结束
and then over in the parse function similar to prams
我们需要解析我们的标题
we need to parse our headers
所以我们会有标题等于
so we'll have headers equals
我们将编写一个名为
and we're going to write a function called
解析标头
parse headers
它会通过
and it's going to pass in
记住的标题行是字符串列表
header lines which remember is a list of strings
那么一旦我们有了这些
then once we have those
当我们初始化我们的 co 和 v 时解析下来
parsed down when we initialize our co and v struck
而我们要设置该字段标题
while we want to set that field headers
作为该标头变量的值
to be the value of that header's variable
所以我们当然需要定义这个函数
so of course we need to define this function
我就这样做
and I'll just do this
就在这里
right down here
接受标题行
takes in the headers lines
最终这将需要返回一个
and ultimately this is going to need to return a
标头图
map of the headers
那么我们将如何做到这一点
so how are we going to do that
好吧，让我们再看看那个请求
well let's look at that request again
所以这样做的传统方法是
so the conventional way to do this would be to
遍历这些标题行
loop through these header lines
这是一个列表
which is a list
将每一行解析为一个键值对
pars each line into a key value pair
所以例如
so for example
这一行的键是主机，值是
this line the key would be host and the value would be
示例 com
example com
然后累积那些键值对
and then accumulate those key value pairs
在标题图中
in the headers map
但事情就是这样
but here's the thing though
长生不老药中没有传统的循环结构
there are no conventional looping constructs in elixir
但请记住在上一节中我们看到
but remember in the last section when we saw that
列出我们的递归数据结构
list our recursive data structures
我已经从之前的视频中重新创建了我们的性爱会话
I've recreated our sex session from the prior video
我们从一个麻木列表开始
and we started with a list of numbs
记住我们使用了头部和尾部
and remember that we used the head and tail
与该 cons 运算符的模式匹配
pattern match with that cons operator
遍历这个列表
to traverse through this list
所以头第一次有一个值
so the first time the head had a value of one
然后 tail 本身就是一个列表
and then tail was a list itself
然后我们在右边使用tail
and then we use tail on the right hand side
然后 head 的值为 2
and then the value of head was two
尾巴是三四和五
and tail was three four and five
依此类推，一直到尾巴的地方
and so on all the way down to the point where tail
是一个元素列表
was a one element list
然后我们将它与该模式匹配
we then matched it against that pattern
头是元素五
and head was the element five
但 tail 是一个空列表
but tail was an empty list
所以每次通过模式匹配尾部
so by pattern matching tail each time
我们递归遍历列表的每个元素
we recursively walked through each element of the list
这是一个做同样事情的简单程序
here's a simple program that does the same thing
它在一个名为 recurred 的独立文件中
it's in a standalone file called recurred
例如，它不在一个混合项目中
ex it's not in a mixed project
你可以找到
and you can find
如果您想跟随它在代码包中
it in the code bundle if you want to follow along
所以它只定义了一个名为 recurse 的模块
so it just defines a module called recurse
它有一个叫做 loopy 的函数
it has a function called loopy
然后我们在这里调用 loopy 并传递给它
and then we call loopy down here and we pass it a
数字一到五的列表
list of numbers one through five
匹配模式
that matches the pattern
这就是这个循环函数中的参数
that's the argument in this loopy function
这给了我们头部和尾部
which gives us the head and the tail
我们打印出头部 打印出尾部
we print out the head print out the tail
然后这是关键部分
and then here's the key part
我们在这里称自己为 loopy
we call loopy on itself here
传入尾部，这是剩余的列表
passing in the tail which is that remaining list
换句话说，它是递归的，如果我们运行它
in other words it's recursive and if we run it
好吧，我们得到相同的输出
well we get the same output
我们很快就进入了 ix
we got in ix just in a little bit
不同的格式
different format
所以你看到它只是
so you see that it's just
递归遍历列表
walking through the list recursively
拔掉头和尾巴
pulling off the head and the tail
直到最后我们得到
until finally we get
到尾巴是空列表的程度
to the point where the tail is an empty list
但是这个函数子句呢？
but what about this function clause air
记得很好
well remember
任何列表的最后一个元素的尾部是
the tail of the final element of any list is
总是一个空列表
always an empty list
所以当它循环时 tail 是一个空列表
so when it loops with tail being an empty list
模式不匹配
the pattern doesn't match
是的
yeah
所以我们需要一个匹配该模式的函数子句
so we need a function clause that matches that pattern
这将有效地终止递归
which will effectively terminate the recursion
我只贴一张
I'm just going to paste one in
所以它是循环的
so it's loopy
有一个空列表
with an empty list
以及何时调用此函数
and when this function is called
因为当我们知道价值时，该模式匹配
because that pattern matches while we know the worth
结束，所以我们只是打印完成
the end so we just print out done
说吧
say that away
再次运行它确定它打印出来完成
run it again well sure enough it prints out done
当我们浏览了整个列表时
when we've walked through the entire list
所以有三种成分可以使这项工作
so there are three ingredients that make this work
第一个是这些多爪功能
the first one is these multi claws functions
这在这里被称为终止爪
this is called the terminating claws here
第二个是我们做模式匹配
the second is we do pattern matching on
头和尾
the head and the tail
这是直到列表为空的模式
this is the pattern up until the list is empty
然后我们在空列表上匹配
and then we match on the empty list
知道我们已经完成了
to know that we're done
最后的成分当然是递归
and the final ingredient of course is recursion
我们在循环自己
we're looping back on ourself
所以要遍历标题行，我们可以递归
so to loop through the header lines we can recurs
两个函数子句的方式相同
the same way with two function clauses
这将在我们的解析器中发生
that's going to happen over in our parser
现在我们解析的标头函数
and right now our parsed headers function
这些标题行接受一个参数
takes one argument these header lines
但我们要改变这一点
but we're going to change this
围绕以匹配模式
around to match a pattern
这将是
it's going to be
首尾
head and tail
然后就像我们需要的递归数一样
and then just like with the recursive numbers we need
最后调用解析头函数
to call the parse headers function as the last
这个函数的行在这里
line of this function here
我们将在尾部通过
and we're going to pass in the tail
记得就像我们做了一个 ix 和那个程序
remember just like we did an ix and that program
我们保持
we keep
在尾部匹配，直到我们到达它的末尾
matching on the tail until we get to the end of it
然后在这条线上
and then above this line
我只是要添加一点调试
I'm just going to add a little bit of debug
这样我们就可以看到发生了什么
just so we can see what's going on
我在这些列表中使用了检查功能
and I'm using the inspect function on these lists
只是
just
因为它会打印出这些列表的原始形式
because it'll print out the raw form of these lists
然后我们也有这些标签头和尾
and then we also have these labels head and tail
周围
around it
当我们的
we also need a second function clause when our
列表返回空
list returns empty
是的，它只是解析标题
yeah it's just parse headers
这将是一个空列表
it's going to be the empty list
在这种情况下，我们将打印出
and in this case we'll print out
就像我们以前做的一样
done just like we did before
所以现在如果我们把它保存起来
so now if we save that away
我们重新编译
and we recompile
我们向上滚动只是为了看看那个调试给了我们什么
we scroll back up just to see what that debug gave us
那么第一次通过头部是
well the first time through the head is
这个主机线和尾巴是所有剩余的线
this host line and the tail is all the remaining lines
然后第二次通过
then the second time through
这是列表中的第二件事
it's the second thing in the list
尾巴就是一切
and the tail is everything else
它只是走过直到最后
and it just walks through until finally
head 是最后一行内容长度
the head is the last line content length
并且尾部是一个空列表
and the tail is an empty list
它与空列表匹配，我们重新完成
and it matches the empty list and we get back done
所以下一个问题是
so the next question is
我们想对每个头部和尾部做什么
what do we want to do for each head and tail
好吧，我们真的没有
well we really don't
关心尾巴
care about the tail
但对于每个头
but for each head
我们想把它解析成一个键值对
we want to parse it into a key value pair
我们知道如何解析字符串
and we know how to parse a string
并匹配返回的列表
and match the returned list
是的，我会在这个调试下面做
yeah I'll just do it down below this debugging
在这里给它一点空间
just give it a little bit of space here
我们的模式将成为价值的关键
our pattern is going to be a key in a value
我们将进行字符串拆分
and we'll take string split
劈头
split the head
这里的难题是冒号和空格
and the dilemma here is a colon and a space
然后我想添加更多的日志记录
and then I want to add a little bit more logging
所以我要复制这个
so I'm just going to copy this
我们会做的
and we'll do it
在我们拥有值中的键之后
after we have the key in the value
我只是要改变这些
I'm just going to change these around
这将是我们的关键
this will be our key
这将是我们的价值
and this will be our value
现在如果我们把它保存起来
now if we save that away
回到这里再次侦察飞行员
come back over here and recon pilot again
并在此处向上滚动
and scroll up here
好的头主机示例
all right head host example
com 并注意我们有密钥
com and notice we have key
好吧，关键是主机，价值是示例
well the key is host and the value is example
com 同样，当我们有这个头时
com similarly when we have the head being this
用户代理线
user agent line
而关键是用户代理
while the key is user agent
值是
and the value is
无论标头中的值是什么
whatever the value of that in the header is
所以我们成功地解析了这个字符串的头部
so we're successfully parsing this string the head
成键值对
into key value pairs
所以接下来我们要做的就是放
so the next thing we want to do is put
标头映射中的键值对
the key value pairs in the header's map
所以我会在这条线下面做
so I'll do that right below this line
我们将像以前一样拥有可变标题
we'll have variable headers like I did before
我早一点把它拿出来了
I took it out a little bit earlier
但我们会把它放回这里
but we'll put it back in here
然后我们想制作一张地图
and then we want to make a map
所以我们将使用地图模块的放置功能
so we're going to use the map modules put function
我们将从一张空地图开始
we're going to start off with an empty map
然后我们将键和值添加到该映射
and then we'll add the key and the value to that map
只是为了多一点调试
and just to give a little bit more debug
我们会做 io 检查
we'll do io inspect
在那些标题上
on those headers
所以让我们再次运行它
so let's run it again
所以这是头部和尾部输出
so here's the head and tail output
这是我们的键值对，然后我们有一个映射
here are our key value pairs and then we have a map
主机是关键示例
host is the key example
com 作为值
com as the value
如果我们低头看这个，这是我们的头和尾
if we look down at this one here's our head and tail
这是关键值
here's the key value
然后我们有一个以用户代理为键的地图
and then we have a map with user agent as the key
但这是一张新地图
but it's a new map
每次是的，这个都有一个关键值
every time yeah this one has one key value
这个有一个关键值
this one has one key value
如果我们继续看这里
if we keep looking through here
它始终是价值的一个关键
it's always one key in value
我们需要一种方法来记住标题的映射并添加
we need a way to remember the header's map and add
每次通过循环
to it each time through the loop
因为我们想要所有的头信息
because we want all the header information
最终出现在一张地图中
to end up in a single map
换句话说，我们需要一种维护状态的方法
in other words we need a way to maintain state
只有一种方法可以做到这一点
and there's only one way to do that
那就是采取国家
and that's to take the state
在我们的例子中是一张地图
a map in our case
并将其作为参数传递给递归函数
and pass it as an argument to the recursive function
在我们这样做之前
before we do that
让我们摆脱这个调试只是为了清理它
let's get rid of this debugging just to clean this up
所以我们可以看到发生了什么
so we can see what's going on
然后我们要改变
then we're going to change
函数抓住第二个参数
the function claws to take a second argument
我们将把它称为标题
and we're going to call it headers
然后而不是调用地图
and then instead of calling map
在这里传入一个空地图作为第一个参数
put passing in an empty map as the first argument here
我们想传入标题
we want to pass in headers
因为我们要添加键和值
because we want to add the key and the value
到这个标题的地图
to this header's map
那么这是关键部分
then here's the key part
当我们递归调用解析头时
when we recursively call parse headers
我们需要传入标题作为第二个参数
we need to pass in headers as that 2nd argument
同样，我们需要将终止爪更改为
likewise we need to change our termination claws to
也拿标题
also take headers
现在当这个终止爪运行时
now when this termination claws runs
这意味着值得列表的末尾
it means worth the end of the list
所以不是打印出来
so instead of printing out done
我们只想返回该标题映射
we just want to return that headers map
它应该包含所有的键值对
and it should have all the key value pairs in it
现在不要忘记
now don't forget
我们需要更新函数调用
we need to update the function call
传入一个空地图
to pass in an empty map
作为第二个论点
as the second argument
所以我们从一张空地图开始
so we start out with an empty map
是的，这里就是这个电话
yeah it's this call right here
它只是传入标题行
it's just passing in header lines
但我们知道我们必须接受两个论点
but we know we have to take two arguments
所以我们要从这个开始
so we're just going to start this off with
空地图
an empty map
所以只是为了通过这个我们称之为部件标题
so just to walk through this we call parts headers
传入一张从这里下来的空地图
passing in an empty map that comes down here
匹配头部和尾部
matches head and tail
接着
and then
我们经过那里积累
we go through there accumulating
此标头映射中的所有键和值
all the keys and values into this header's map
把它传回给自己
passing it back to itself
直到最后 Bing
until finally Bing
我们得到从解析头返回的最终头映射
we get the final header map returned from parse headers
所以现在如果我们把它保存起来
so now if we save this away
回来重新编译
come back over and recompile
我们会检查一下
we'll check it out
这是我们的 co 和 v 结构，它有一个标题
here's our co and v structure and it has a headers
字段，该字段的值是一个地图
field and the value of that field is a map
包含我们所有的标题
containing all of our headers
现在
now
如果你用其他语言做过这样的递归
if you've done recursion like this in other languages
您可能会担心以这种方式反复出现
you might be concerned that recurring this way
足够大的列表可能会消耗大量内存
with a large enough list could consume a lot of memory
并炸毁调用堆栈
and blow up the call stack
但因为最后
but because the last
该函数所做的就是调用自己
thing the function does is call itself
Elixir 使用了一种叫做尾调用优化的东西
elixir uses something called tail call optimization
没有新的帧被推入调用堆栈
no new frames are pushed onto the call stack
所以它不会消耗额外的内存
so it consumes no additional memory
换句话说，这在长生不老药中真的很有效
in other words this is really efficient in elixir
所以现在我们已经收集了所有的标题
so now that we've collected all the headers
我们可以回到我们原来的问题
we can return to our original problem
如果内容类型与此匹配
if the content type matches this
然后我们可以继续我们的解析
then we can proceed with the parsing we
已经有解析部分
already have in parse parts
但如果不是那么我们将忽略
but if not then we'll ignore
请求正文或参数字符串
the request body or the param string altogether
并做到这一点
and to do that
我们将使用
we're going to use
模式匹配中的多爪函数
multi claws functions in pattern matching
所以我们要做的就是改变
so what we'll do is we'll change
这个函数
this function to
将内容类型作为第一个参数
take the content type as the first argument
这样我们就可以对其进行模式匹配
and that way we can pattern match on it
然后当我们在这里调用 parsh para 时
and then when we call parsh para which happens up here
好吧，我们将把标题映射中的值传递给它
well we'll pass it the value that's in the headers map
与密钥相关联
associated with the key
内容类型
content type
所以如果内容类型是这个应用程序
so if the content type is this application
x wow form url 编码
x wow form url encoded
好吧，我们想解码它
well we want to decode it
使用我编码查询功能
using that I code query function
但我们还需要定义一个
but we also need to define a
所有其他内容类型的默认子句
default clause for all other content types
所以它会被称为pars para
so it's going to be called pars para
我们并不真正关心内容类型是什么
and we don't really care what the content type is
我们甚至不关心参数字符串
and we don't even care about the param string
因为如果我们跌到这个水平
because if we fall through to this level
好吧，我们只是要返回一个空地图
well we're just going to return an empty map
因为我们要匹配这个
because we're going to match this one
我们将以我们知道的方式处理它
and we're going to handle it the way we know how
通过解码它
by decoding it
但对于其他一切
but for everything else
好吧，我们不知道如何处理
well we don't know how to deal with that
所以我们只是要返回一个空地图
so we're just going to return an empty map
现在如果我们把它保存起来，它应该像以前一样运行
now if we save this away it should run just as it did
前
before
确实如此
and indeed it does
但是让我们改变我们的 post 请求的内容类型
but let's change the content type of our post request
让它成为一个多部分斜线表单数据
let's make it a multi part slash form data
如果我们现在运行它
if we run it now
我们看到 para 和预期的一样是空的
we see that the para is empty just as expected
是的
yeah
这是 Web 服务器处理的另一种内容类型
this is another content type that web servers handle
但它要复杂得多
but it's a lot more complicated and
真的没有什么新东西可以教
there's really nothing new to teach about
灵丹妙药通过实施
elixir by implementing that
再加上它可能需要很长时间才能完成
plus it probably takes a long time to do
所以我要把它放回去
so I'm just going to set it back
并说我们只处理这种内容类型
and say that we just handle this content type
递归是长生不老药的基本组成部分
recursion is a basic building block of elixir
你会看到它被广泛使用
and you'll see it used extensively
但你不会经常用它来
but you won't often use it to
像我们一样遍历和处理列表
traverse and process the list as we did
是的，这种代码很常见
yeah this kind of code is so common
e 新模块提供了便利的功能
that the e new module provides convenience functions
用于操作列表
for manipulating lists
从细节中提供一个非常好的抽象
providing a really nice abstraction from the details
但在底层实现了 e 新功能
but under the hood the e new functions are implemented
使用递归
using recursion
我们将看看接下来即将推出的 e 新模块
we'll have a look at the e new module coming up next